[Music]
hello friends
welcome back to our channel
i am your tosca instructor and my name
is kumaresh
i have total 14 years of it experience
in software development and test
automation thank you for connecting with
us
hope you are doing well
let's start our today's session
through this video i will explain the
overview of tosca
library concept of reusable test step
block
and business parameters
the explanation of reusable test step
block creation will be done through
demonstration
to understand the tosca library
completely we need to understand few
more related concepts in tosca
such as
test step block is a grouping of test
steps to perform a specific task such as
login logout create record etc
the test step block can be created using
the test case level folder
it helps to increase the readability and
reduces the efforts for maintenance
library is acted as a container of
reusable test step blocks
the library can be created within any
folder available in test case section
but more than one library cannot be
created within single folder
the icon of the library is similar to
testcase folder with symbol l
reusable test step block when we define
a test step block within the library
section it's acted as reusable test step
block
we can create it in two ways
such as either new reusable test step
block creation in library or convert
existing test step block by drag and
dropping any existing test step block
into library
business parameter it's an approach to
pass test data into the reusable test
step block through this parameter
with the help of business parameters we
can use the reusable test step block for
a different set of test data
now i will show how to create the
library reusable test step blocks with
business parameters in an existing
automated test case
we will create the reusable test step
block with the test case which was
created previously
first we will select and check out the
parent folder for modification
create the library component by clicking
on create test step library icon with l
symbol after right clicking on the
parent folder
[Music]
now right click on library folder and
create reusable test step block with a
logical name
we are providing name as google search
as we are going to create reusable test
step block for google search
functionality
we will add two test steps by dragging
from test case for searching text in
google and wait for search result
we can place this reusable test step
block in the test case by drag and drop
method
next step is to create the business
parameter to pass the test data
in order to do that first business
parameters component to be added
[Music]
then we can create the parameter as
search text to pass the search text from
test case to reusable
assign this newly created search text
parameter to the test step in reusable
test step block by drag drop to replace
the hard-coded test data
so the creation of reusable test step
block with business parameter is now
completed
go to the test case and pass the search
text try sentence tosca in the reference
of reusable block
now we will see how to parameterize the
test data using the test case
configuration parameter and pass it as
business parameter value
first go to the test configuration
section and create a test configuration
parameter as search text
[Music]
after that assign the value as trisentis
tosca to this parameter
now go to test case details section and
select the reference component of
reusable test step block
[Music]
replace the hard-coded value which was
passed to reusable component with the
newly created test configuration
parameter search text
similarly we can create multiple test
configuration parameters in a test case
based based on the requirement
[Music]
thanks for watching this video
that's all about tosca library reusable
test step block
and business parameters to manage test
data
we will learn more about tosca buffers
in next video
please visit our website lambdageeks.com
for more articles on technology
engineering mathematics and various
other domain
you can check our other website as well
[Music]
we have features like youtube trends
twitter trends
scientific calculator and many more
other tools
[Music]
if you like our video please like
comment and share
if you have any questions please comment
and we will resolve your query